

📞 508-591-5426 🧔 asadkhan0@protonmail.com

Summary

intermediate level skills in the field. Possess strong technical, project management, communication, and analytical skills. I can define and author robust test cases, automated scripts, test plans and reports. I have a solid understanding of defect tracking, triaging and classification as they are discovered. I am able to define problems, collect data, establish facts, and draw valid conclusions. I am committed to ensuring comprehensive testing is performed to assure the quality of an application's usability, functionality, security, and performance. I am open to combining my professional experience with my areas of interest in cloud and platform engineering provided a suitable opportunity presents itself.

I am a Software Quality Assurance Engineer with several years of test experience and

Experience

Philips Healthcare Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Nov 2015 - Current Cambridge, MA

https://www.usa.philips.com/healthcare

- Creating and executing test cases for new product features as well as performing

regression testing against existing features.

requirements, work as intended and operate within quality management limits and standards.

Document test plans, optimize test suites and create test summary reports.

Testing application functionality to ensure that systems and applications meet user

Perform unit, system, integration and performance tests as well as data migration for major and minor product releases.

Document and communicate issues identified during testing activities to development

teams and assist with defect triaging and resolution. Identify and recommend process/application improvements to management.

ZOLL Medical Corporation Design Quality Assurance Engineer

July 2012 - Nov 2015

Chelmsford, MA

https://www.zoll.com/

Support various testing activities, test planning, project estimation and scheduling, resource planning, training, and oversight, test development, test execution, defect management, daily/weekly status reporting, and project closure.

Contribute to SQA metrics such as requirements coverage, test case readiness, test

- execution progress and defect count statistics in test management tool. Attending project status meetings and provide SQA status, work with PM to define SQA
- tasks and estimates for the project schedule. Ensure comprehensive testing for product usability, functionality, security and
- performance.

Education

Projects

Skills

Interests

Certifications

Publications

Languages

University of Ottawa Biomedical Engineering 8.0 out of 10.0

2009 - 2012 Masters

https://www.uottawa.ca/en Thesis project on advanced optical biosensors for early detection of Leukemia and Lung

Cancer.

Photonics Engineering 8.8 out of 10.0

Algonquin College

2005 - 2009 **Bachelors**

https://www.algonquincollege.com/ Studied advanced optical and electro-optical concepts as well as applications in the field of

Web application fundamentals

bio-chemistry, telecommunication and various other fields.

Online Tool Aggregator

https://toolsnirvana.com

A website to collect various productivity and A.I. tools

HTML, CSS, JS, Node, MongoDB, Firebase, SQL

SDLC phases in Agile and Waterfall Environments

Defining, deploying and executing test plans

Test Management Tools • • • • 0

MTM, IBM Rational DOORS Familiarity with Bug Reporting Systems

Jira, Azure Boards, Microsoft TFS

Cross functional work experience • • • • •

DevOps, Development, UI/UX, Automation Low Code / No Code Testing Systems

• • • 0 0 Provar, Copado, Selenium

Learning new technologies

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

DevOps, Platform Engineering, No Code App Builders, Blockchain, Cloud

Google **Provar Essentials**

CTFL ASTQB

Applied Physics Letters

2016

2022

2022

Provar

Mach-Zehnder refractometric sensor using long-range surface plasmon waveguide

Sensing of bacteria immobilized under static conditions using long-range surface plasmon waveguides in CYTOP

SPIE Characterization of Biosensing waveguides on CYTOP

SPIE

Co-author on: Fabrication of surface plasmon waveguides and integrated components on

CYTOP

Microelectronic Engineering (Elsevier)

English Spoken, Written, Comprehension

Urdu

Spoken, Written, Comprehension

• • • •